Red Riding Hood. The Woodsman. Granny. The Wolf. Not Your
Typical Crime. Not Your Usual Suspects.
Hoodwinked! is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Cory Edwards.
Little Red Riding Hood: A classic story, but there's
more to every tale than meets the eye.
Before you judge a book by its cover, you've got to flip through the pages.
In the re-telling of this classic fable, the story begins at
the end of the tale and winds its way back.
Chief Grizzly and Detective Bill Stork investigate a domestic disturbance at Granny's cottage,
involving a karate-kicking Red Riding Hood, a sarcastic wolf and an oafish Woodsman.
Red (voice), played by Anne Hathaway.
Granny (voice), played by Glenn Close.
The Wolf (voice), played by Patrick Warburton.
The Woodsman (voice), played by Jim Belushi.
Nicky Flippers (voice), played by David Ogden Stiers.
Chief Grizzly (voice), played by Xzibit.
Hoodwinked!
is a 2005 American animated musical comedy film directed by Cory Edwards
and written by Edwards, Todd Edwards, and Tony Leech.
It retells the folktale "Little Red Riding Hood" as a police procedural,
using backstories to show multiple characters' points of view.
The film features the voices of Anne Hathaway, Glenn Close, Jim Belushi, Patrick Warburton,
Anthony Anderson, David Ogden Stiers, Xzibit, Chazz Palminteri, and Andy Dick.
Hoodwinked!
was among the earliest computer-animated films to
be completely independently funded.
Working apart from a major studio allowed the filmmakers greater
creative control, but also restrained them economically.
Due to the film's low budget, its animation was produced in the
Philippines with a stylized design inspired by stop motion films.
The Weinstein Company did not sign on as the film's distributor until near the end of production, and while the
company had several roles recast with higher-profile actors, it otherwise made few changes to the film.
Structurally, the film was inspired by non-linear crime
dramas, such as Rashomon and Pulp Fiction.
It was released shortly after the first two installments in the successful Shrek series by
DreamWorks Animation, which accentuated the fairy tale parody genre of which Hoodwinked!
Hoodwinked!, however, intentionally deviated from the Shrek series
in its style of humor and in certain plot elements.
This was in part based on Cory Edwards' concerns over exposing children
to the high level of cynicism often found in the genre.
The film was released in Los Angeles and Philadelphia on December 16, 2005, for a
one-week engagement, before expanding nationwide on January 13, 2006.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was a commercial
success, grossing $110 million against an $8M budget.
A sequel, Hoodwinked Too!
Evil, was released in 2011.
The film explores themes of wolf, investigation,
suspicion, villain, little red riding hood.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.